Finding Aid for the Poster Collection LSC.0095
UCLA Library Special Collections
Poster collection
1890 - 2021
UCLA Library Special Collections
LSC.0095
9 oversize boxes
1.25 linear feet (3 unprocessed oversize boxes)
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Collection assembled by the staff of UCLA Library Special Collections.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942336063606533
Scope and Content
Collection consists of an assemblage of posters, primarily 20th century American and European. Includes travel posters, exhibit posters, and war posters from World War I France, and American posters from World War I and World War II.
Posters.
- [Aesop Fable. The Tortoise and the Hare] Beverly Hills, Ca.: Pacific Answering Service, [197-?]., 1 print. (Box 71)
  Scope and Contents note
  Telephone answering service advertisement, Beverly Hills, California, Pacific Answering Serice
- AGFA. We never forget a face., 1 item. 24 wide × 36 high. (Box 71)
  Poster showing the AGFA Postscript Type Collection. Thousands of faces on disk or CD-ROM.
- American Indian. Art show advertisement, 1974.; 1 item. (Box 71)
- American World War II posters., 20 items. (Box 77)
  Russian War Relief (17 posters).
  1 Russian War Relief box.
  1 clothing depot sign.
  1 map of the USSR.
- Amon Carter Museum, Fort Worth, Texas, 1961-1977.; 1 item. (Box 71)
  Poster commemorating the opening of a new wing of the museum.
- Arizona. University. Center for Creative Photography. Exhibit poster for, September 25-October 30 [1977?].; 1 item. (Box 71)
- Art--California--Galleries and Museums., 1 item. (Box 73)
- Art--California--Galleries and Museums., 10 items. (Box 71)
  Miscellaneous posters advertising art exhibits in California (includes an exhibition poster for Beth Van Hoesen).
  General note
  (1 additional poster in folder 73).
- Art--Los Angeles., 2 items. (Box 73)
- Art--Los Angeles--Galleries and Museums., 12 items. (Box 71)
  Miscellaneous posters advertising various art exhibits in and around the greater Los Angeles area.
  (2 additional posters in folder 73).
- Baird, Bil. Exhibit poster, October 7-December 15, 1976.; 1 item. (Box 71)
  Poster for an exhibit of Bil Baird's puppets at UCLA's Department of Special Collections, Los Angeles.
- Burkhardt, Hans. Exhibit posters, September 21-October 24, 1975.; 2 items. (Box 71)
  In honor of Mr. and Mrs. Hans Burkhardt at California State University, Northridge
- California Welcome Fleet., 1 print. (Box 65)
- Valentine Vox the ventriloquist. By Henry Cockton, Esq. 60 richly humourous plates. Sold by all booksellers. [London? ], ca. 1840?; 1 item. 51 × 39 cm. Poster. (Box 71)
  Advertisement for the book published in Penny numbers weekly.
  Cf. Sadlier no.3472.
- [Los Angeles?: Art Attack, between 1980 and 2000?] ([Pasadena: Typecraft, Inc.), 7 prints. (Box 71)
- Cook, James, 1728-1779. v.p., v.d.; 3 items. (Box 71)
  Miscellaneous posters commemorating various exhibits.
- Eiko Ishioka: Blood, Sweat, and Tears—A Life of Design, 2020 - 2021 (Box 71)
- Era of Exploration: The Rise of Landscape Photography in the American West, 1860-1885., 1 item. (Box 71)
- European Posters, ca. 1958-1973.; 4 items. (Box 50)
  Theater, opera, and art gallery exhibit posters.
- European posters. Theater, opera, and art gallery exhibit posters., ca. 1958-1973.; 55 items. (Box 51)
- Les Farfadets. International puppet show presented by the French Expedition Alexandre, 193?.; 3 items. (Box 71)
- French Advertisements, 1925-1937.; 8 items (mostly folded). (Box 70)
- French Advertisements, 1930s.; 7 items (mostly folded). (Box 69)
- Armée de Paris, habitants de Paris, les membres de Gouvernement de la République ont quitté Paris.... / Paris, le 3 Septembre 1914. / Le Gouverneur Militaire de Paris, Commandant l'Armée de Paris, Galliéni. [Paris]: Gouvernment Militaire de Paris, 1914? (Paris: Imprimerie Marcel Picard)., 1 print: 1 color (black); 65 x 50 cm. (Box 82)
  Text only. This may be a later reproduction.
- Aux habitants du Nord de la France / Le Maréchal Von der Goltz fait connaître aux populations du Nord de la France...que le choléra sérit avec intensité dans les troupes alliés.... / Charleville, le 20 Septembre 1914 / Von der Goltz, Maréchal. [S.l.]: Imprimerie Régionale, 1914?, 1 print: 1 color (black); 57 x 39 cm. (Box 82)
  Text only. This may be a later reprint.
- Le vin chaud de l'arrière à l'avant ... nous vaincrons en le buvant! [S.l.]: Ministère de l'agriculture, [191-]., 1 print: color; 61 x 41 cm. (Box 82)
  Signed in lower right: (difficult to read - Plau? Ploz? N. Lain?). Bottom right edge: "exempté du timbre_VISé par la censure".
- Les Alsaciens et les Lorrains sont Français! [text blocks]. Paris: J. Cussac, Imp., [1914]., 1 print: color; 73 x 45 cm. (Box 82)
  Signed in lower right of image: "L. Jonas". At lower left: "VISA No. 11.922". Alsace and Lorraine were lost to Germany in the Franco-Prussian war of 1870-71 (from LC record). Block of text below image is regarding the history of the Alscae-Lorraine region and its association to the rest of France. LC has this poster and alternate version with different title and text block but same image. Date from LC record.
- Les revendications des bébés. [S.l.]: Croix-Rouge Américaine Bureau des Enfants, [191-] ([Paris: Imp. G Bataille])., 1 print: 1 color (dark blue); 73 x 52 cm. (Box 82)
  Picket signs read: "Nous voulons / Le lait de Maman / Les soins de Maman / Des sages-femmes competents / Des parents sain / Etre proteges des mouches / Des couches seches / Dormir seuls / Etre nourris regulierement / De l'air et du soleil / Qu'o[n] nous laisse tranquilles / Vivre en bonnes sante." Signed in lower right of image: "Jacques Carlu." Printing information at bottom cut off. Cut down from 80 x 60 cm (measurements of LC copy).
- Nous voulons vivre / aidez nous! / 80,000 bébés français périssent chaque année. [S.l.]: Croix-Rouge Américaine Bureau des Enfants, 1917 ([Imp. G Bataille. Paris])., 1 print: color; 80 x 60 cm. (Box 82)
  Signed in lower left of image: "R. (H.?) Stéphany 1917". Bottom right of poster: "VISA No 9743"
- Ordre du jour du 6 Septembre 1914 / "Au moment où s'engage une Bataille dont dépend le salut du pays, il imports de rappeler a tous que le moment n'est plus de regarder en arrière. Tous les efforts doivent être employés à attaquer et à refouler l'ennemi.... Dans les circonstances actuelles, aucune défaillance ne peut être tolérée." / - Joffre. Paris: Librarie du Musée de la Guerre, 1914?, 1 print: 1 color (black); 65 x 50 cm. (Box 82)
- Ordre du jour du Général Joffre le 2 Août 1916 / Soldats de la République! Votre troisième année de guerre commence. Depuis deux ans, vous soutenez, sans faiblir, le poids d'une lutte implacable.... La victoire est certaine! / Joffre. Paris: Impr. Du Musée de la Guerre, 1916?, 1 print: 1 color (black); 65 x 50 cm. (Box 82)
- Réservez le vin pour nos Poilus. [S.l.]: Comité National de Prévoyance & d'Economies, [1916] (Paris: Union Française)., 1 print: color; 56 x 38 cm. (Box 82)
  Signed in lower right of image: "Suzanne Ferrand (16 ans)". At bottom left of image: "Ville de Paris. Ecole, Boulevard Pereire 221". At very bottom: "cette affiche ne doit pas être vendue". Date from LC record.
- Sauvons les bébés par l'allaitement maternel. [S.l.]: Croix-Rouge Américaine Bureau des Enfants, [1917?] ([Imp. G Bataille. Paris])., 1 print: 1 color (dark brown); 80 x 60 cm. (Box 82)
  Signed in lower right of image: "R. (H.?) Stéphany". Bottom left: "VISA No 9742".
- Fullerton, California. Muckenthaler Cultural Center. Specific Observations--Sights Unseen. poster for exhibit, February 5-March 12, 1978.; 1 item. (Box 71)
- Gallo Vineyards. A Loaf of Bread, a Jug of Wine, & Thou. 1976-1977 school year calendar poster. Gallo Vineyards, Modesto, California, 1 item. (Box 71)
- Germany. Deutsche Industrieausstellung. Berlin., 1968.; 1 item. (Box 71)
  Poster for industrial exhibit.
- Girlie Movie Theater Ads, ca. 1960s.; 2 items. (Box 56)
- Girlie Movie Theater Ads, ca. 1960s.; 3 items. (Box 55)
- Overland mail route to California ... Portland, H.W. Corbett, 1866.; 1 item. 33.5 × 24 cm. Poster. Framed 43.5 × 33.5 cm.
  Text printed in red and blue with black and white woodcut of stagecoach drawn by 6 horses.
  [In map room (JF May 2003)].
- Black oak books [picture] / [designed by] Lance Hidy; printed by Rob Day. -- West Lebanon, New Hampshire: Mink Brook Editions, c. 1985.; 1 poster: 7 colors; 86 × 42 cm. (Box 71)
  Silk-screen poster depicts woman in rocker reading to child sitting at her feet. -- Signed and numbered in pencil. -- Edition: 383/600.
- The Hugh M. Morris Library rededication October 11, 1986 [picture] / design [by] Lance Hidy; printed by Rob Day. -- West Lebanon, New Hampshire: Mink Brook Editions, c. 1986.; 1 poster: 8 col.; 86 × 43 cm. (Box 71)
  Silk-screen poster commemorates rededication of the Hugh M. Morris Library, University of Delaware, Newar, Delaware -- Signed and numbered in pencil. -- Edition: 39/222.
- Italian Posters., 4 items. (Box 73)
- Jews in California., 1 item. (Box 71)
- Ketchem, Robert Glenn., 1 item. (Box 71)
  Poster for photo exhibit in Venice, California.
- Kilbride, Vincent folder. Rancho Santa Monica, 1976.; 1 item. (Box 71)
  Hand-painted silk-screened poster commemorating an event in the history of Santa Monica, California, presentation copy.
- Lange, Dorthea, 1895-1965. Looking at Lange today. Great Hall, Oakland Museum, Oakland, California, July 4-August 20, 1978.; 1 item. (Box 71)
- London. Underground and rail posters., 3 items.
  (Rolled, level B)
- Los Angeles County. Museum of Natural History, 1978.; 3 items. (Box 71)
- Los Angeles. Public Library...Robert Nathan., 1 item. (Box 71)
- Masreel, Frans, 1889-1971. West German Political Poster, 1951.; 1 item. (Box 71)
- McGovern for President '72., 1 item. (Box 71)
- Miscellaneous political posters--U.S. and England., 10 items. (Box 71)
  - Voilà les Américains! L'Allemagne aurait voulu rompre le front occidental et imposer aux Allies des conditions de paix aussi honteuses que celles imposées à la Russie. Il est trop tard! L'effort Américain depasse toutes les prévisions. Ce que nous apporte l'Amérique ... Nancy; Paris: Berger-Levrault, [1917]., 1 print: color; 50 x 65 cm. (Box 71)
    At bottom: strip of six boxes of pictures and text showing what war support America gives to France. Signed in lower left of image: "Saunier". Stamp on back: "AFFICHES- ESTAMPES F. PIGEON 6[7?], Rue de Richelieu". Date from LC record.
- Miscellaneous posters., 26 items. (Box 57)
- Miscellaneous Posters., 36 items. (Box 58)
- Motion picture posters--French., 5 items. (Box 71)
- Music (Rock) posters, 1967.; 51 items. (Box 71)
- Neimans, Joyce. Maid in LA., 1 item. (Box 71)
- New World Utopias, 1975-76.; 1 item. (Box 72)
  From photo exhibit by the California Historical Society.
- Nin, Anaïs, 1903-1977., 3 items. (Box 72)
- Olympic Games, Los Angeles, 1932.; 1 item. (Box 73)
- Philippines, Ladrones, Hawaii & Puerto Rico, illustrated throughout with 52...Sears Roebuck Company. []., 1900 (Box 72)
- Photography exhibitions., 1 item. (Box 73)
- Photography Exhibitions., 14 items. (Box 72)
  (Includes an exhibition poster for Walker Evans, James Van Der Zee, Imogene Cunningham)
  (An additional poster in folder 73).
- Polish Political Posters, vol.2, 1971-1975.; 24 items. (Box 72)
- Polish Political Posters, vol.1, ca. 1946-1973.; 25 items. (Box 72)
- Renaissance Pleasure Fair, Southern California., 6 items. (Box 72)
- [Rock Concerts.] Mostly printed in Northern California: issued by Bill Graham Presents, Family Dog, Neon Rose (Moscoso), or other local groups, dated 1966, or 1967, or undated., 47 prints: color; measuring around 51 x 36 cm. and 62 x 36 cm. (Box 81)
  Artists: Victor Moscoso, Wes Wilson, Bonnie MacLean, Rick Griffin, Stanley Mouse (also Mouse Studios, Kelly-Mouse), Gomez, George Hunter, John H. Myers, Peter Bailey, and photographs of Herb Greene. Some of the groups advertised: Grateful Dead, Quicksilver Messenger Service, Moby Grape, Miller Blues Band, Howlin' Wolf, Charlatans, Chambers Bros., Doors, Country Joe and the Fish, Sparrow, Canned Heat.
- Russian posters, ca. 1945-.; 8 items. (Box 79)
- Russian posters, ca. 1945-.; 8 items. (Box 78)
- Russian propaganda for children, ca. 1929-1931.; 9 items. (Box 72)
- San Francisco Public Library., 1 item.
- San Francisco: The Mechanics Fair of San Francisco, (6 pieces); California Welcome Fleet., 1896; 7 items. (Box 65)
- Shahn, Ben, Ben Shahn: A retropective, 1898-1969., 1 item. (Box 72)
- Spanish Language, 1940s-1950s.; 5 items. (Box 66)
- Stein, Gertrude, 1874-1946.; 1 item. (Box 72)
  Poster for exhibit by Richard Crawford.
- Strand, Paul, 1890-1976. Exhibit Poster, []., 1977?; 2 items. (Box 72)
- [Los Angeles, other California, and New York Theater] [California (including L.A.), New York Theater posters. 7 items., 7 prints. (Box 71)
- Times Change Press--political posters by various artists, 1970.; 8 items. (Box 72)
- Travel Posters--Britain, 1950s?.; 45 items. (Box 64)
- Travel Posters--France, 1930s-1950s.; 13 items. (Box 61)
  - France. France: by and for the French Government, [ca.1951] (Paris: Imprimerie Georges Lang)., 1 print: 1 color (black); 99 x 62 cm. (Box 61)
    Under photo at right: "PH. COMPAGNIE AERIENNE FRANCAISE." Photo caption: "Paris L'Arc de Triomphe de L'Etoile." Under title: "Ministère des Travaux Publics des Transports et du Tourisme Commissariat Général au Tourisme."
  - Maroc / Terre de grand tourisme. Rabat; Paris: Office Marocan du Tourisme, [between 1930 and 1960] (Paris: E. Desfosses Néogravure)., 1 print: color; 99 x 65 cm. (Box 61)
    Signed: "R. Génicot."
  - Maroc. Rabat: Office Marocain du Tourisme, [between 1930 and 1960] (Paris: Imprimerie Georges Lang)., 1 print: 1 color (black); 99 x 60 cm. (Box 61)
  - Maroc. [Rabat; Paris?]; Office Marocain du Tourisme, [between 1930 and 1960] (Irabat: Perceval Editions Africaines)., 1 print: color; 100 x 62 cm. (Box 61)
    Signed in lower right: "EVEN."
  - Paris is 2000 years old / 1951. France: by and for the French Government, 1951 (Paris: Imp. S.A. Courbet)., 1 print: color; 60 x 39 cm. (Box 61)
    Signed in lower right: "Chaplain-Midy."
  - Paris is 2000 years old / 1951. France: by and for the French Government, 1951 (Paris: Imp. S.A. Courbet)., 1 print: color; 110 x 62 cm. (Box 61)
  - The sun spends the winter on the French Riviera. France: by and for the French Government, [between 1930 and 1960] (Paris: Bedos & Cie. Imprimerie)., 1 print: color; 99 x 65 cm. (Box 61)
    Signed in upper left: "Dubois" (possibly Dubuis). At bottom: "Ministère des Travaux Publics des Transports et du Tourisme _ Commissariat Général au Tourisme."
  - Winter sports in France. France: by and for the French Government, [between 1930 and 1960] (Paris: E. Desfossés Néogravure), 1 print: color; 99 x 63 cm. (Box 61)
    Signed: "jean léger." At bottom: "Ministère des Travaux Publics et des Transports -- Commissariat Général au Tourisme."
- Travel Posters--France, 1914-1950s.; 15 items. (Box 59)
- Travel posters--France, Air France (15); French Line (14)., 1947 1930s; 29 items. (Box 60)
  - "Bits of France afloat" / All the charm and atmosphere of France pervades the ships of the French Line Compagnie Général Transatlantique. U.S.A.: [s.n.], 1933., 1 print: color; 65 x 45 cm. (Box 60)
    "Drawn especially for the French Line by Adolph Treidler." At bottom: "F-268 March 1933."
  - Air France / Amérique du Nord. Paris: Herbert Baille & Cie., [19]46., 1 print: color; 99 x 62 cm. (Box 60)
    Signed in lower left: "GUY ARNOUX [drawing of anchor]." At bottom margin: "013/P./AF. (2-46)."
  - Air France / Amérique du Sud. Paris: Perceval, [194-?]., 1 print: color; 100 x 62 cm. (Box 60)
    Attributed to Victor Vasarely. At bottom margin: "015/P/AF."
  - Air France / De jour et de nuit, de nuit et de jour, dans tous les ciels / nox post lucem lux post noctem. Paris: Perceval, 1938?, 1 print: color (including gold); 62 x 99 cm. (Box 60)
    Unsigned but Lucien Boucher did similar designs for other Air France posters. Image caption: "Principales lignes exploitées en 1938-1939." At bottom margin: "Il a été tiré de ce planisphère 200 exemplaires numérotés de 1 a 200."
  - Air France / French West Africa French Equatorial Africa. France: Goossens Publicité, [19]47., 1 print: color; 99 x 62 cm. (Box 60)
    Signed in lower right of image: "E. MAURUS." At bottom: "127-P-5/47."
  - Air France / Near East - Far East. Paris: Perceval, [19]47., 1 print: color; 100 x 62 cm. (Box 60)
    Signed in lower left: "LUCIEN BOUCHER." At bottom margin: "119/P/6-47.
  - Air France / North Africa. Paris: Hubert Baille & Cie., [19--]., 1 print: color; 100 x 62 cm. (Box 60)
    Signed in lower right: "Villemot [drawing of arrow or bow]." At bottom: "109/P/AF."
  - Air France / Towards new skies. Paris: Perceval, [19]47., 1 print: color; 99 x 62 cm. (Box 60)
    At bottom: "120/P/6-47."
  - Air France / West Africa Equitorial Africa. Paris: Alépé et Cie., [194-]., 1 print: color; 100 x 62 cm. (Box 60)
    Signed in lower left: "Guerra" (?). Attributed by some to Vincent Guerra. At bottom: "022/P/AF."
  - Air France covers the world. France: Goossens Publicité, [19]47., 1 print: color; 99 x 61 cm. (Box 60)
    Signed in top right: "E. MAURUS." At bottom: "128-P-5/47."
  - Air France. Paris: SNAP, [19]47., 1 print: color; 99 x 65 cm. (Box 60)
    Signed in lower right of image: "HERVé BAILLE [drawing of anchor]." At bottom: "123-P.6-47."
  - All the charm and atmosphere of France pervades the ships of the French Line Compagnie Général Transatlantique / Veritable "bits of France afloat" / New York - Plymouth - Havre. U.S.A.: [s.n.], 1939., 1 print: color; 66 x 49 cm. (Box 60)
    At bottom: "F268-A Jan. 1939."
  - Along the way of TWA. [S.l.]: Trans World Airlines, c1950 (U.S.A.)., 1 print: color; 56 x 43 cm. (Box 60)
    At bottom: "Color-foto by Trans World Airlines." Image caption: "Eiffel Tower at Paris."
  - Normandie / Cie. Gle. Transatlantique French Line / Le Havre - Southampton - New York. Paris: Alliance Graphique L. Danel, [19]35., 1 print: color; 100 x 62 cm. (Box 60)
    Signed in upper right: "A.M. Cassandre 35."
  - Paris / Air France. [Paris?]: La Générale Publicité, [19]47 (Paris: Imp. Bedos & Cie.)., 1 print: color; 100 x 62 cm. (Box 60)
    Signed in lower right: "P. BADOUIN *47*."
  - Paris via Constellation / World leader in speed, comfort, safety. [S.l.: Trans World Airlines?, between 1945 and 1960] (U.S.A.)., 1 print: color; 99 x 67 cm. (Box 60)
    Signed in lower right: "MAXIMUS."
  - The gentle art of civilized living / Beaches the highest degree of perfection aboard the ships of the French Line / "Bits of France afloat." U.S.A.: [s.n.], 1939., 1 print: color; 63 x 45 cm. (Box 60)
    At middle right: "Drawn especially for the French Line by Adolph Treidler." Image caption: "The cocktail bar of the Champlain." At bottom: "268-B Jan. 1939."
- Travel Posters--Spain, 1929-1932.; 15 items. (Box 67)
- Travel Posters--Spain, 1929-1950, 1964.; 13 items. (Box 68)
- Travel Posters--various European, 1930-1960s.; 13 items. (Box 62)
  - Berlin is calling the world / Visit the city of the Freedom Bell. Germany: Graaf (?), [19]51?, 1 print: color; 97 x 64 cm. (Box 62)
    At upper right: "GRAAFF BAF" (artist or printer?). At bottom: "Printed in Germany 10 51 10."
  - Göta Canal / Sweden's scenic waterway. Sweden: Meyer & Köster, Västsvenska Kartonnage S.B. [between 1930 and 1940?]., 1 print: color; 100 x 63 cm. (Box 62)
    At upper left: circle with line extending from bottom ending with downward facing bracket; upward facing bracket in middle of line (artist's mark?).
  - Gotland Sweden Visby Festival July - August. Sweden: Foreningen Ruinspelen I Visby in cooperation with Gotland Tourist Association and Swedish Tourist Traffic Association, 1960 (Sweden: Wezäta)., 1 print: color; 100 x 61 cm. (Box 62)
    At right under image: "Photo: E. Nordström Foto AB." Photograph caption: "Scene from the mystic pageant opera "Petrus de Dacia" by Friedrich Mehler."
  - Hamburg American Line / Mediterranean cruises by S.S. Ariadne February - June 1958. Hamburg, Germany: Johler-Druck, 1958., 1 print: color; 84 x 60cm. (Box 62)
    Signed in lower left: ANTON HAMBURG."
  - London via Constellation / World leader in speed, comfort, safety. [S.l.: Trans World Airlines?, between 1945 and 1960] (U.S.A.)., 1 print: color; 100 x 66 cm. (Box 62)
    Signed in lower left: "Noël Quinn."
  - Northern Sweden. Sweden: Swedish Tourist Traffic Association in co-operation with the local tourist associations concerned, [ca.1960] (Sweden: Wezäta), 1 print: color; 100 x 62 cm. (Box 62)
  - Norway / The land of the midnight sun. [S.l.]: Norwegian State Railway, 1939 (Oslo, Norway: Norsk Lithografish Officina)., 1 print: color; 99 x 62 cm. (Box 62)
    Signed in lower right: "IVAR GULL."
  - The best bells in the world / Bell Foundry Van Bergen Heiligerlee Holland. Winschoten [Groningen, Netherlands]: Van der veen, [between 1940 and 1960]., 1 print: color; 50 x 39 cm. (Box 62)
    Photograph caption: "St. Martin's Church 230 Lenox Avenue New York 27. The tower contains a Ven Bergen Carillon 41 bells."
  - Welcome to Denmark, Norway, Sweden, and Finland / Scandinavian student organizations co-operate with USNSA in arranging student tours! Finland: Milori Ltd., [between 1940 and 1960]., 1 print: color; 84 x 62 cm. (Box 62)
- Travel Posters--v.p., 1930s-.; 12 items. (Box 63)
  (Japan, Turkey, Israel, Belgian Congo, etc.)
  - Belgian Congo and Ruanda - Urundi. Bukavu, Belgian Congo: Tourist Bureau for the Belgian Congo and the Ruanda - Urundi, [between 1950 and 1970] (Brussels: De heneffe)., 1 print: color; 100 x 62 cm. (Box 63)
  - Cuzco. Peru: Touring y Automovil A.I.A.C.R. Club del Peru, [between 1930 and 1960] ([S.l.]: Empresa Grafica T. Schevch S.A.)., 1 print: color; 95 x 60 cm. (Box 63)
    Signed in lower left: "AGOSTINELLI."
  - Indian detours on the way to or from California. [S.l.]: Santa Fe Railroad, [between 1930 and 1960]., 1 print: 1 color (brown); 92 x 61 cm. (Box 63)
    Santa Fe round logo in lower right.
  - Israel / Eilat on the Red Sea. Israel: E. Lewin Epstein Ltd., [19]59?, 1 print: color; 98 x 68 cm. (Box 63)
    Signed: "Kor 59."
  - New York World's Fair / The World of Tomorrow 1939. [New York?]: New York World's Fair, 1939 (New York City: Grinnell Litho. Co.; Lipaba Union Label)., 1 print: color; 76 x51 cm. (Box 63)
  - Streamliners link the West / Super Chief, Chief, El Capitan, Chicagoan, Kansas Cityan, San Diegan, Golden Gate. [S.l.]: Santa Fe Railroad, [between 1930 and 1960]., 1 print: 1 color (dark green); 92 x 61 cm. (Box 63)
    Santa Fe round logo with Chief behind at lower left.
  - Turkey / Rumeli Fortress overlooking the Bosphorus. [Turkey?]: Turkish Press Broadcasting and Tourist Department, [between 1940 and 1960]., 1 print: 1 color (black); 90 x 59 cm. (Box 63)
- Trilby A novel by George Du Maurier, with one hundred and twenty illustrations by the author. [New York] Harper & Brothers, ca. 1894.; 1 item. 48 × 32 cm. Poster. (Box 72)
  Advertisement for the book.
  Special Collections has a catalogued copy of the New York edition.
- U.S. Department of Interior. National Park Service., 11 items. (Box 74)
  American Revolution Bicentennial.
- United Nations., 16 items. (Box 53)
- United Nations., 15 items. (Box 52)
- United Nations (37), UCLA Library, Microfilm Cataloging (3)., 40 items. (Box 54)
  (Assembled by Helen Jane Jones & Jeannette Hagen, 1946)
- Barrie's Sentimental Tommy, in Scribner's [New York]., 1895?; 1 poster. 44 × 32 cm. (Box 72)